{
  "forest": {
    "quiz1": [
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "Tropical moist forests do not include which of the following?",
        "options": [
          "Broadleaved forests",
          "Wet evergreen forests",
          "Semi-evergreen forests",
          "Moist deciduous forests"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Broadleaved forests"
      },
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "Which of these is not a use value?",
        "options": [
          "Direct value",
          "Indirect value",
          "Option value",
          "Existence value"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Existence value"
      },
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "The value derived from the knowledge of use of resources by others in the current generation is called?",
        "options": [
          "Altruistic value",
          "Bequest value",
          "Existence value",
          "Option value"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Altruistic value"
      },
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "Montane sub-tropical forests do not involve which of the following?",
        "options": [
          "Broadleaved forests",
          "Pine forests",
          "Semi-evergreen forests",
          "Dry evergreen forests"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Semi-evergreen forests"
      },
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "\"Pant community, predominantly comprised of trees and other woody vegetation, usually with a closed canopy\" is?",
        "options": [
          "Silviculture definition of forests",
          "FAO definition of forests",
          "Legal definition of forests",
          "Ecological definition of forests"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Ecological definition of forests"
      },
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "Which of these is not a consumptive value?",
        "options": [
          "Timber",
          "Firewood",
          "Non-timber forest products",
          "Education"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Education"
      },
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "The term 'forest' originates from?",
        "options": [
          "Latin foris meaning outside",
          "Greek foris meaning outside",
          "Latin foris meaning trees",
          "Greek foris meaning trees"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Latin foris meaning outside"
      },
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "The value of leaving use and non-use values for offspring's or future generation is called?",
        "options": [
          "Altruistic value",
          "Bequest value",
          "Existence value",
          "Option value"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Bequest value"
      },
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "Which of these is not a forest type found in India?",
        "options": [
          "Mediterranean dry",
          "Tropical dry",
          "Montane temperate",
          "Alpine"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Mediterranean dry"
      },
      {
        "subject": "forest",
        "quizNumber": 1,
        "question": "According to the Supreme Court, the term 'forest land' includes?",
        "options": [
          "Some area recorded as forest in the government record according to ownership",
          "Any area recorded as forest in the government record according to ownership",
          "Some area recorded as forest in the government record irrespective of ownership",
          "Any area recorded as forest in the government record irrespective of ownership"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Any area recorded as forest in the government record irrespective of ownership"
      }
    ]
  }
}